Ke Qian alex

∓ Rogers AR⋈ ke@mnch.xyz**↓** 189 1557 7634**ೂ** gh/xenialaq

Work Experience

Walmart GeC, Global Integrated Fulfillment

Software Engineer III (Automation)

2018.06 - 2020.11 AR

Develop a comprehensive UI automation solution based on Node.js and Appium and enable automation on GIF app modules. The test solution features multi-env & multi-remote support, test data DSL & dynamic data generation, performance monitoring, and support for Promise & async, CI, JIRA, BDD etc.

The data-driven solution efficiently handles hundreds of test orders per minute. A wide collection of JavaScript support code streamlines the access of microservices and allows full lifecycle control of orders. Reduced running time by managing orders, devices and API accesses through pipelines and parallelization.

Adapt from Walmart and third-party solutions to reduce development & test maintenance cost. Enabled an in-house alternative to minimize disruption upon issue with a key SaaS provider, and repurposed the SaaS solution as a candidate for BYOD testing. Work with developers for better UI testability and system stability. Onboard testers to automation and optimize it based on feedback. Finalize test plans & scopes with cross-functional teams. Provide guidance on test case writing and scripting. Support continuous learning and collaboration by allocating works, organizing demos, enforcing standards and best practices, etc.

Cornell University, Language Resource Center

Developer 2017.06 - 2018.05 NY

Built and maintained WALAT (WAL Authoring Tool), a courseware creator for Web Audio Lab, an online learning platform. Before, rich media courses required Web development skills and manual compilation of texts, scripts and media. Usually Center staff acted as authors due to high demand from intstructors.

WALAT was written in Angular to streamline the courseware creation process with sets of forms, page templates, drag-and-drop command editor and an asset manager for embedding media files. A desktop version was made with Node, SQLite and Electron without costing extra server resources.

WalmartLabs

Tools and Automation Intern

2016.06 - 2016.08 CA

Developed SRT, a full-stack Java project visualizing test results.

SRT retrieves data from TestRail API and Jenkins DB, aggregates and stores them using Hibernate, and exposes RESTful endpoints with which the dashboard can visualize automation & test stats and drill down using filters. Optimized chart loading time by caching SQL query results. Created an admin UI to manage configs and scheduled tasks.

Sam's is still using SRT for test reporting and SRT was adapted for GIF backend E2E testing.

Education

Cornell University

Master's - Information Science - GPA: 3.26

2017.08 - 2018.05 NY

Project Microsoft Azure · A browser-based cluster configurator for Azure Service Fabric on-prem users Led a team of 3 and worked closely with the client to visualize cluster hierarchy with D3.js and Matter.js the physics engine. Support for drag-drop, WYSIWYG, two-way conversion between designer and JSON editor, and JSON Schema validation to notify users of missing or incorrect fields.

Cornell University

Bachelor's - Computer Science, Information Science - GPA: 3.12

2013.08 - 2017.05 NY

Honors Fall 2014 Dean's List

MATLAB Consultant 2016.08 - 2017.05

Student Assembly Tech Committee Developer

2015.10 - 2016.06

Highlights

Five years of Web development experience and two years of mobile testing experience. Most recent product concerns operation of 5000 stores in US, UK, MX, CA.

Proficient in JavaScript (Node.js), ES6+ features and common frameworks (Express, RN). Working knowledge of Java development. Full stack project experience with Grails and Spring frameworks.

Experience with Linux environment (Shell), CI/CD, microservices, SQL, NoSQL, RESTful, WebSocket, MQ technologies. Familiar with algorithms and data structures, past experiences with DBMS, operating systems, data analysis (Python). Able to utilize PaaS & SaaS solutions and forge partnership with service providers. Excellent English proficiency.

Languages Mandarin Chinese, English

钱可 alex

▶ 软件开发方向 辛 江苏 苏州 ☑ ke@mnch.xyz

L 189 1557 7634 n gh/xenialaq

工作经历

Walmart GeC, Global Integrated Fulfillment

沃尔玛电商全球集成送配

自动化测试工程师III

2018.06 - 2020.11 阿肯色

提出并开发了基于 Node.is 和 Appium 的前端自动化测试解决方案,分析团队需求并加以定制,在多个 GIF 应用模块普及了自

对关键代码二次开发,使该测试解决方案支持多环境、多平台,测试数据 DSL 和动态数据生成,性能监测,并且支持 Promise / async, CI, JIRA 和 BDD 等特性。

将数据驱动与解决方案深度融合,使其能高效处理每分钟数以百计的测试订单。构建了一系列 JavaScript 套件,简化了对企业 内微服务架构的访问,实现了数据采集、生成、查询、接收的端到端全链路把控。

通过对测试订单、测试设备、API 访问的集中管理,管线化和并行处理,缩短了前端集成测试的耗时,以便在迭代周期内及时 收集和报告软件缺陷,溯源,复测及验收。

向公司及第三方方案汲取经验,降低研发和维护成本。在SaaS方案遇阻时果断采用自身与公司内部方案同时推进,确保自动 化测试不中断。在 BYOD 项目落地后又逐步恢复与第三方的合作。

与开发者沟通,提高应用的可测性与系统的可靠性。帮助测试者熟悉自动化测试并根据反馈进行优化。和团队敲定测试计划、 范围、环境。对测试用例和代码编写予以指导。通过任务细分,组织展演,制定标准化流程和最佳实践等方式支持团队建设和

Cornell University, Language Resource Center

康奈尔大学语言中心

开发者

2017.06 - 2018.05 纽约

为 Web Audio Lab(一个线上外语学习平台)编写和维护一个课件制作器(WALAT,WAL Authoring Tool)并创作课件。 在此之前,复杂的多媒体课件要求作者有网页开发的能力,并将课件内容,脚本和多媒体文件手动打包上传。通常中心雇员会 充当作者,往往难以满足课程讲师们的需求。

WALAT 提供了多种风格的表单、页面模板,可拖拽式指令编辑器及用于嵌入多媒体资源的管理器,大大简化了用户的创作流 程。该 Web 应用运行于本地而不依赖服务器,并且为了便于分发,使用 SQLite 和 Electron 构建了一个桌面版本。

WalmartLabs 沃尔玛实验室

工具与自动化实习生

2016.06 - 2016.08 加州

开发了SRT,一个提供测试结果数据可视化图表的 Java (Grails) 全栈项目。

SRT 从 TestRail API 和 Jenkins 数据库调取数据,通过 Hibernate 和 MySQL 将数据持久化, 最终以 RESTful 服务的形式供仪表 板使用。Web 仪表板可以实现对自动化和测试通过情况的概括性分析,并可通过测试集、时间等参数查找到具体的执行情况。 通过对 SQL 语句结果进行缓存,加快了图表的载入速度,并据此开发了后台界面来容纳不同的配置和计划任务。

首发用户山姆会员店仍然在使用 SRT 汇总测试结果,并且 SRT 经过容器化改造后被用于 GIF 后端的测试。

教育背景

Cornell University

康奈尔大学

硕士 - 信息科学 - GPA: 3.26

2017.08 - 2018.05 纽约

Microsoft Azure·基于 Web 的面向本地部署 Azure Service Fabric 的用户的群集配置工具 带领三人团队和客户接洽,使用开源的 D3.js 和 Matter.js 物理引擎可视化呈现了群集的层次结构,支持拖拽和编辑视图元素, 支持可视化设计器和 JSON 编辑器之间的互转。代码编辑器提供了基于 JSON Schema 的验证功能来提示用户缺失或错误的字 段。

Cornell University

康奈尔大学

学士 - 计算机科学, 信息科学 双专业 - GPA: 3.12

2013.08 - 2017.05 纽约

荣誉 Fall 2014 Dean's List (2014秋季院长奖)

2016.08 - 2017.05

MATLAB 课程顾问

2015.10 - 2016.06

学生会技术部开发者

技能其他

语言能力

汉语普通话,英语

专业技能

五年的 Web 前端项目开发经验和两年的移动端测试开发经验。所涉产品运用于美英墨加近 5000 门店。

精通 JavaScript(Node.js),熟悉 ES6+ 特性和常用框架 (Express,Swagger)。熟悉 Java 编程,使用 Grails 框架实施过全栈

熟悉Linux环境(Shell),CI/CD,微服务的布设。经常接触 SQL、NoSQL、RESTful、WebSocket、消息队列等技术。 了解常用的数据结构及算法,有 DBMS、操作系统、数据分析(Python)等过往经验。

能够在项目中运用 PaaS、SaaS 等解决方案,和服务提供商保持良好合作。英语交流表达能力出众。